Stealth Technology, the Internet, GPS in the palm of your hand, autonomous operation
隐形技术、互联网、手掌上的GPS、自主操作
Technology is a driver of our times since its founding in 1958, in the midst of the cold war, DARPA the defence advanced research project agency has been a driver of technology.
技术是我们这个时代的驱动力，自1958年成立以来，在冷战中，DARPA--国防高级研究项目机构一直是技术的驱动力。
Welcome to Voices from DARPA, a window onto the DARPA's core of program managers, their job to redefine was possible
欢迎来到《来自DARPA的声音》，这是一个了解DARPA的核心项目经理的窗口，他们的工作是重新定义可能。
My name is Ivan Amato. I'm  your DARPA host
我的名字是伊万-阿马托。我是你们的DARPA主持人
On this occasion, I've invited my colleague in DARPA's public affairs group Tabatha Thompson to join me as a co-host as we speak to doctor Timothy Chung, who joined the DARPA as a program manager in 2016.
这次，我邀请了我在DARPA公共事务组的同事塔巴塔-汤普森和我一起担任共同主持人，我们将采访2016年加入DARPA担任项目经理的博士蒂莫西-钟。
You might hear some ambient sounds like birds or sirens
你可能会听到一些环境声音，如鸟类或警笛声
That's because recording our conversation from our respective homes, as we do our part to slow the spread of Covid19, as the pandemic has abandoned our daily routines
那是因为在我们各自的家中录制了我们的谈话，我们正在为减缓Covid19的传播而努力，因为这种大流行病已经放弃了我们的日常工作
Work continues on more than 250 programs
250多个程序的工作仍在继续
Each was a vision of useful technology that's out of reach at the moment, but could become within reach in the future.
每一个都是对有用技术的设想，这些技术目前还遥不可及，但在未来可能变得触手可及。
Tabatha, you've been working closely with Dr. Tim Chung to help get word out about his program
塔巴莎，你一直在与蒂姆-钟博士密切合作，帮助他的项目传出消息
So why don't you take it from here?
那么你为什么不从这里开始呢？
Thank you, Ivan.
谢谢你，伊万。
I have been lucky to have a front row seat to the progress on two of those programs, OFFensive Swarm-Enabled Tactics, OFFSET for short and the DARPA of Subterranean challenges or SubT challenge for short.
我很幸运能在前排看到其中两个项目的进展，OFFensive Swarm-Enabled Tactics，简称OFFSET，以及DARPA of Subterranean challenges或简称SubT challenge。
For the OFFSET program, two teams have developed two different swarm systems, open architectures in physical testbeds.
对于OFFSET计划，两个团队已经开发了两个不同的蜂群系统，在物理测试平台中的开放架构。
The program also has what I called swarms sprinters, organizations competitively selected through contract opportunities to focus on a particular technology through sierra
该计划也有我所说的蜂群冲刺者，即通过合同机会竞争性地选择的组织，通过Sierra专注于一项特定的技术
About every six months,
大约每六个月一次。
The program hosts a field tests for the sprinters to demonstrate and further develop their solutions
该计划为冲刺者举办一次现场测试，以展示和进一步发展他们的解决方案
The SubT challenge is a price base challenge, with teams from all over the world competing, in the systems competition with physical platforms,
SubT比赛是一个价格基础的挑战，来自世界各地的团队在有物理平台的系统竞争中进行竞争。
the virtual competition, or in both.
虚拟竞赛，或同时进行。
Team score when the robots accurately identified artifacts, a first responder or a war fighter might encounter underground like a backpack, drill or a thermal manikins(人体模型)
当机器人准确地识别出人工制品时，团队就会得分，一个急救人员或一个战争战士可能会在地下遇到像背包、钻头或热能人体模型这样的东西。
representing a survivor.
代表一个幸存者。
Tim, thank you for joining us to talk about your work.
蒂姆，感谢你加入我们，谈论你的工作。
Yeah, it's a pleasure to be here.
是的，很高兴来到这里。
Thank you so much
非常感谢你
I'd like to hear more about your programs and technologies you're working toward
我想听到更多关于你的项目和你正在努力的技术。
But I'd like to start with your research trajectory and how you came to DARPA
但我想从你的研究轨迹和你如何来到DARPA开始说起
You have degrees in mechanical and aerospace engineering
你有机械和航空航天工程的学位
But where did your interest start?
但你的兴趣是从哪里开始的？
And are there any significant influences that could be people or events that stand out for you?
是否有任何重要的影响，可能是对你有突出影响的人或事？
Yeah, well, I mean, I think I always
是的，我的意思是，我认为我总是
really appreciated and was curious about how the world works.
真的很欣赏，对世界如何运作感到好奇。
And from that perspective, being an engineer means that we not only need to understand how things worked, but also also wants to try to fix them
从这个角度来看，作为一名工程师，我们不仅需要了解事物的工作原理，而且还想尝试修复它们
if we can, of course, and come up with new ideas.
当然，如果我们能做到的话，并提出新的想法。
And so I think a lot of the excitement that goes on around robotics also touched me, especially as a undergrad where I had a chance to work on the Cornell University Robotic soccer team.
因此，我认为围绕机器人技术的许多兴奋点也触动了我，尤其是在本科阶段，我有机会在康奈尔大学机器人足球队工作。
And that led to whole new experiences and really understanding what it means
这使我获得了全新的体验，并真正理解了将技术变为现实的意义。
to make the technology real
使技术成为现实
This is granted about playing robots soccer, but it meant that people had to come together, share ideas, worked together and then create the sets of robots that were doing,
这是授予关于玩机器人足球，但这意味着人们必须走到一起，分享想法，一起工作，然后创建正在做的成套机器人。
or be something really fun with a soccer, but doing a purpose
或者是一些非常有趣的足球，但是有目的的。
and that really inspired me to continue that line of research.
这真的激发了我继续研究这条路线。
Could you go from that experience with robot soccer to coming to DARPA as a program manager?
你能不能从机器人足球的那段经历中走出来，来到DARPA担任项目经理？
The inspiration perhaps comes all the way back when my sister was a sophmore at west points, and I just started my first year in grad school
灵感也许可以追溯到我妹妹在西点大学读大二的时候，而我刚刚开始读研究生的第一年
And that's when I am eleven hit
那是我11岁的时候。
And I knew at that point, my sister being part of that, army would soon to be called upon to action,
我知道在那个时候，我妹妹是其中的一部分，军队很快就会被要求采取行动。
and it was really hard for me to sit in this supposed Ivory tower of academia, and think that my kid sister would be fighting, you know, this war
对我来说，坐在学术界的象牙塔里，想到我的妹妹要去打仗，你知道的，这场战争，真的很难受。
and ponder(仔细琢磨) a lot about whether or not to, unless myself, pondered what I could do to serve my country in that sense
思考了很多关于是否要，除非我自己，思考我可以做些什么来为我的国家服务。
And I remember my mentor at the time said, I totally understand if you want to, or need to enlist(参军), you know, go, go, do that
我记得当时我的导师说，我完全理解，如果你想，或者需要参军，你知道，去吧，去吧，做吧
but remember that there is this opportunity that the work that you do here, in pursuit of your advanced degrees, can ultimately, potentially do more and serve more and have deeper impact
但请记住，有这样一个机会，你们在这里做的工作，在追求你们的高级学位时，最终有可能做得更多，服务更多，影响更深。
And I think, from that point toward, I saw that my sister went into hammers' way, but I remain in grad school, finish my degree
我认为，从这一点来看，我看到我的妹妹进入了锤子的方式，但我仍然在研究生院，完成我的学位
continue to always have in the back of my mind that I wanted to make the world a slightly safer, better place
继续在我的脑海中始终有一个想法，我想让世界变得更安全、更美好。
And I think that let me to pursue in my position, my faculty position at the Naval post-graduate school,
我认为这让我在我的位置上追求，我在海军研究生院的教员职位。
which allowed me to explore mission relevance, research problems while also engaging with junior officer core, which is incredibly rewarding,
这使我能够探索任务的相关性，研究问题，同时也与初级军官核心接触，这是令人难以置信的回报。
and then also ultimately led to a research portfolio there that brought exposure to
然后也最终导致了在那里的研究组合，使我接触到了DARPA的机构，并从DARPA的机构中获得了一些经验。
the institution of DARPA and from that interaction, was able to find my way ultimately to DARPA to hopefully realize some of that quest that was inspired many many years ago.
从这种互动中，我最终能够找到进入DARPA的途径，希望能够实现许多年前被激发的一些追求。
You've given a couple of examples of how your career interacted with DARPA before you actually join the agency as a principal investigator, and also not honesty
你已经给出了几个例子，说明在你真正加入DARPA作为主要研究人员之前，你的职业生涯是如何与DARPA互动的，也没有诚实的例子
But knowing the team that was participating in a DARPA challenge, when you are at CalTech.
但知道参加DARPA挑战的团队，当时你在加州理工学院。
Could you talk a little bit about how those experiences, in addition to those life experience, but I think were so important to informing your work, how they influence the way you shape the programs that you run for the agency.
你能不能谈一谈这些经验，除了这些生活经验之外，但我认为对告知你的工作是如此重要，它们如何影响你塑造你为该机构运行的项目的方式。
It takes me back to think about the DARPA grand challenge
这让我回想起在我还是研究生的时候，DARPA的大挑战
while I was a grad student
当我还是个研究生的时候
I saw, this announcement about this audacious(大胆的) effort to take robots and driving across the desert in autonomous fashion
我看到这个公告，关于这个大胆的努力，让机器人以自主方式驾驶穿越沙漠
And I remember thinking, and I was just a junior grad student, but leaning over to my fellow student Pierre saying
我记得我在想，当时我只是一个低年级的研究生，但俯身对我的同学皮埃尔说
wow, this is really cool, and then discovered that the CalTech would be fielding(选派..上场) a team largely comprising undergraduates
哇，这真是太酷了，然后发现加州理工学院将派出一支主要由本科生组成的队伍。
But I still remember the inspiration of that challenge offered to me and my fellow graduate students and undergraduate student, and I think that kind of nugget of inspiration was something that continued burning
但我仍然记得那个挑战给我和我的研究生同学以及本科生带来的灵感，我认为那种灵感的小块是持续燃烧的东西。
I think, it continues to be there and drives us to go and do
我认为，它继续存在，促使我们去做
sometimes really audacious things, and given this opportunity to come to DAPRA
有时真的很大胆的事情，有了这个机会来到DAPRA
and have the opportunity to go off and do those types of audacious things that really inspired the nature of both of my programs
并有机会去做这些类型的大胆的事情，真正激发了我两个项目的性质。
I think was able to work at the Naval post-graduate school, which I would really like to be an incubator
我认为能够在海军研究生院工作，我真的希望它成为一个孵化器
really great ideas
真正伟大的想法
We have junior officers who have a lot of fleet experience
我们有初级军官，他们有很多舰队的经验
They come to getting their gradual level education.
他们来获得他们的渐进式教育。
They bring with them a lot of experiences that meet academic research,
他们带来了大量的经验，满足了学术研究。
And boom, you have a really great fusion of need, and state-of-the-art
然后，你有一个真正伟大的需求和最先进的融合。
And from my perspective seeing, NPS as an incubator
从我的角度看，NPS是一个孵化器
I view DARPA as an accelerator of those ideas, really take those ideas and run with them a bigger, bolder, faster.
我认为DARPA是这些想法的加速器，真正采取这些想法，并以更大、更大胆、更快的方式运行。
This is a good point for us to talk a little bit more about the programs in your portfolio SubT challenge and OFFSET offensive swarm enabled tactics,
这是一个很好的点，让我们多谈一点关于你的投资组合中的项目SubT比赛和OFFSET进攻性蜂群启用战术。
the obvious tie between the two is this focus on the autonomy and robotics
两者之间的明显联系是对自主权和机器人技术的关注。
But there are some significant differences in the outcome goes too,
但在结果上也有一些明显的区别。
for instance, the focus on human swarm teaming in OFFSET
例如，OFFSET中对人类蜂群团队的关注。
Could you talk through some of these common teams, and then also some of the key differentiators for these two programs?
您能谈谈这些共同的团队，以及这两个项目的一些关键区别吗？
Sure. OFFSET is a program where we seek to discover the swarm system technologies
当然，OFFSET是一个我们寻求发现蜂群系统技术的项目
that will allow operates of hundreds of 250 air and ground robots operating in complex urban environments in support of small unit operations
这将允许在复杂的城市环境中操作数百个250个空中和地面机器人，以支持小单位的行动。
The Subterranean challenge is all about discovering innovative approaches to map, navigate and search in complex underground environments.
地下挑战是关于发现在复杂的地下环境中绘图、导航和搜索的创新方法。
I think the unifying theme and what drives me is to see robots in the real world, operating in complex environments.
我认为统一的主题和驱动我的因素是看到机器人在现实世界中，在复杂环境中运作。
I think robotics is one of those fields where you can't just only work in theory, or you can't only work in kind of Trial and error.
我认为机器人学是这样一个领域，你不能只在理论上工作，或者你不能只在试验和错误中工作。
You kind of need to bring both of them together and see robot working in the wild.
你需要把这两者结合起来，看到机器人在野外工作。
And so I think that's something that really inspires me is obtaining that strict, not something that we, roboticst, really embrace is seeing robots work.
因此，我认为这是真正激励我的东西，是获得那种严格的，而不是我们Roboticst真正接受的东西，是看到机器人工作。
Until the key emphasis for both OFFSET and SubT challenge
直到OFFSET和SubT比赛的关键重点
is putting robots in really challenging environments in a field, robotic sense and seeing what they have to do, where the gaps might still be for what they're not yet able to do.
是把机器人放在真正具有挑战性的环境中，从机器人的角度来看，看看它们必须做什么，它们还不能做什么，差距在哪里。
So for OFFSET we're interested in those really complex urban environment,
因此，对于OFFSET，我们对那些真正复杂的城市环境感兴趣。
specifically those aspects of the urban mess that stress autonomy today.
特别是今天城市混乱的那些方面，强调自主性。
And that includes everything from the fact that you might not have a line of sites,
而这包括一切，从你可能没有场地线的事实。
because the building in the way you can't move as freely, because there is a lot of obstacles or things, blocking in your lanes,
因为建筑物挡住了你的去路，你不能自由行动，因为有很多障碍物或东西挡住了你的车道。
and the fact that you have to look up and around, because you have the superstructures(上部结构) all around this, well
而事实上，你必须仰视和环顾四周，因为你有上层建筑(上部结构)在这周围，好吧。
And so, how do you get air and ground robots working in that kind of environment?
因此，你如何让空中和地面机器人在这种环境下工作？
And then on top of that, and because this is DARPA, we'd like to push the envelope.
此外，由于这是DARPA，我们想挑战一下极限。
how do we get hundreds of robots to be able to go off and do those kind of things in a complex environment?
我们如何让数以百计的机器人能够在复杂的环境中去做这些事情？
I think the similarity with the Subterranean challenge is the [inaudible] these underground environments are equally complex
我认为与地下挑战的相似之处在于[听不清]这些地下环境同样复杂
And not only are they complex, in the sense of, hey, we don't typically spend a lot of time in underground environments
它们不仅是复杂的，从这个意义上说，我们通常不会在地下环境中花费很多时间
one might argue, but also the fact that the unknown underground, it makes it even dangerous for people to go in
人们可能会说，但事实上，地下的未知性，使得人们进入地下更加危险。
And so this is an opportunity for again, robots, to, to shine
所以这又是一个机会，机器人可以大显身手了
And so whether those are in human-made tunnel-like environment, such as mines, to urban underground to naturally occurring cave environments.
因此，无论这些是在人类制造的类似隧道的环境中，如矿井，城市地下，还是自然发生的洞穴环境。
This is an opportunity for, again, robots to understand what the current limitations of autonomy and robotics are today,
这是一个机会，再次，机器人了解目前自主性和机器人技术的限制是什么。
and really inspired the type of researchers as necessary to conquer those environments in the future
并真正激发了研究人员在未来征服这些环境所需的类型。
I think both of the programs offered the opportunities for roboticst, but also just brought the researchers, geologists, city planners, even kind of micro climate researchers,
我认为这两个项目都为机器人提供了机会，但也带来了研究人员、地质学家、城市规划师，甚至是微型气候研究人员。
to speak to what impact a holistic(整体的) systems design
谈到了整体的系统设计的影响。
And when I say systems, I'm not talking just about one robot
当我说系统时，我不是在说一个机器人
I'm talking about all the robots working together
我指的是所有的机器人一起工作
The team, the humans supervisor
团队，人类的监督者
or the human-swarm team member, understanding how that holistically comes together to deliver the capabilities that will help save lives in the end.
或人类-蜂群团队成员，了解如何从整体上一起提供能力，以帮助最终拯救生命。
Could I get you to talk a little bit more about human-swarm teaming, and just describe what's that looks like
我可以让你多谈一点关于人与群的合作，并描述一下这看起来像什么？
Yeah, I'm an autonomy researcher is, is, however, described myself.
是的，我是一个自主性研究者，是的，无论如何，我自己描述。
But in thinking about autonomy and swarm autonomy, in the sense of having large scale teams of robots makes air and ground working together
但在思考自主性和蜂群自主性时，在拥有大规模的机器人团队的意义上，使空气和地面一起工作
We can't leave the human out of it because how we design that autonomy is impacted by how we envison the human swarm commander, working with a technology
我们不能把人排除在外，因为我们如何设计自主性会受到我们设想的人类蜂群指挥官的影响，与一项技术一起工作。
And so the OFFSET program intentionally focuses on those two pillars of swarm autonomy and human teaming
因此，OFFSET项目有意将重点放在蜂群自主性和人类团队合作这两个支柱上。
And in that sense, the OFFSET programs about discovering what it means when you have hundreds of robots operating in a complex environment
从这个意义上说，OFFSET计划是为了探索当你有数百个机器人在复杂环境中工作时意味着什么。
and the intense of the program is to kind of understand, you know what works and what doens't work
该计划的目的是要了解，什么是可行的，什么是不可行的。
We certainly cannot have 100 or 200 marines runing around with joysticks in conducting and urban operation
我们当然不能让100或200名海军陆战队员拿着操纵杆跑来跑去，进行城市行动。
So what does it mean when we try to consolidate(巩固) a lot of that team member commander role for large-scale teams of robot,
那么，当我们试图为大规模的机器人团队整合很多团队成员的指挥官角色时，这意味着什么？
what, what does it mean?
这意味着什么？
Does it mean..
这是否意味着...
We present information in a different way?
我们以不同的方式呈现信息？
Does it mean that they have to interact with the robots at a much higher level,
这是否意味着他们必须在更高的层次上与机器人互动。
and so the way we think about it in the OFFSET program is in the context of translating commanders intents into these machine-understandable swarm tactics
因此，我们在OFFSET项目中考虑的方式是将指挥官的意图转化为这些机器可理解的蜂群战术。
These swarm tactics give us a glimpse as to how we can potentially interact
这些蜂群战术让我们看到了我们如何能够与这些大型团队进行潜在的互动
with these large scale teams, and ultimately boils down to understanding what the language we called the swarm interaction grammar
与这些大规模团队的互动，并最终归结为理解我们称之为蜂群互动语法的语言。
What is the language by which the swarm can understand
蜂群可以通过什么语言来理解
the commander is trying to get done, commander's intent,
指挥官想要完成的任务，指挥官的意图。
and conversely(相反地), the commander understanding what the swarm's actually doing.
反之，指挥官也能理解蜂群的实际行动。
is it doing what I ask it to on things of a nature, so the two ways tree, and that's why we call it the human swarm teaming, it is not a human swarm control
它是否在做我要求它做的事情，所以这两种方式的树，这就是为什么我们称它为人类蜂群团队，它不是一个人类蜂群控制。
It's really about interaction between the human and the swarm
它实际上是关于人类和蜂群之间的互动。
And so we imagine also that it's not just going to be a screen with a mouse
因此，我们还设想，它不仅仅是一个带有鼠标的屏幕
that's gonna solve this problem of interacting with these large scale teams
来解决与这些大规模的团队互动的问题
You know, gesture or voice or augmented and virtual reality
你知道，手势或语音或增强型和虚拟现实
Maybe these are other tools that we can now take advantage of to help inform how we interact with these large-scale teams
也许这些都是我们现在可以利用的其他工具，帮助我们了解如何与这些大规模的团队互动
For the SubT challenge, it's an extended event, so it's over a couple of years
对于SubT比赛，它是一个扩展的事件，所以它是在几年的时间里
that you are working with these teams.
你正在与这些团队合作。
And you divided it up into circuits.
你把它分成了几个回路。
Could you talk a little bit about your goal for each of the circuits and how you divided the challenge?
你能谈谈你对每条线路的目标以及你如何划分挑战吗？
Well as I mention we're really interested across my DARPA program portfolio of putting robots in the real world and having them operate in complex environments.
正如我提到的，我们对我的DARPA项目组合非常感兴趣，把机器人放在现实世界中，让它们在复杂的环境中运作。
And when we take another look at underground environments,
当我们再看一下地下环境。
There are so many different types of underground environments that just to solve the problem in one of the domain wouldn't be enough.
有这么多不同类型的地下环境，仅仅解决其中一个领域的问题是不够的。
I really ought to understand and identify what works and what doesn't work in underground environments.
我真的应该了解并确定在地下环境中哪些是可行的，哪些是不可行的。
And so what we've done is for the SubT challenge we highlighted that there're underground environment like tunnels and mines
因此，我们所做的是，对于SubT比赛，我们强调有地下环境，如隧道和矿井。
We've articulated(清楚表达) there're urban underground environments
我们明确表达了有城市地下环境
They are natural occuring cave systems and trying to figure out what kind of robotic technologies will allow us to operate relatively adaptively across all three of those types of underground environments
他们是自然发生的洞穴系统，并试图找出什么样的机器人技术可以让我们在所有这三种类型的地下环境中进行相对适应性的操作。
So what that boils down to is, how do we capture all of that
因此，这归结为，我们如何捕获所有这些东西
And so one way to do that is to focus on each individuals of domain
这样做的一个方法是专注于每个领域的个体
and we're doing that in the context of three circle domains, namely the tunnel circuit, urban circuit and upcoming, we have a cave circuit. But, as I highlighted, it's not about being the best swimmer were the best runner
我们在三个圈域的背景下这样做，即隧道回路、城市回路和即将到来的洞穴回路。但是，正如我所强调的，这不是关于成为最好的游泳者或最好的跑步者。
It's really about being the best Triathlete(铁人三项运动员) here
而是要成为最好的铁人三项运动员（Triathlete）。
And so we want to see how these individual events in form the designs, and even the concept of operations for those technologies
因此，我们想看看这些单项比赛是如何形成设计的，甚至是这些技术的操作概念。
But it's at final event where we will be able to merge elements of all three of those sub domains into the grand finale, epic final course,
但在最后的活动中，我们将能够把所有这三个子领域的元素合并到压轴的、史诗般的最终课程中。
and understand what it means to have truly adaptive technology, robotic systems that can upgrade across those sub domains.
并理解拥有真正的自适应技术、能够跨这些子领域升级的机器人系统意味着什么。
Tim, both of your programs really inspired the imagination to think of all of this kind of interaction with with you are human beings and with machines all trying to work together to, you know, in new ways
蒂姆，你的两个项目真的激发了人们的想象力，去思考所有这种与你是人类和机器的互动，都试图一起工作，你知道，以新的方式。
The SubT, though, also comes to my mind as a kind of fascinating and endeavour(努力) that it forces you to think about being underground, right in most of the time
不过，SubT也让我想到了一种迷人的努力，它迫使你思考在地下的问题，就在大部分时间里。
We think about being on the surface [..] or an plains all the time
我们一直在考虑在表面[......]或平原上的问题
But it's rare unless you're a spelunker, caver
但是，除非你是一个洞穴探险家，否则很少有机会真正思考在地下的问题。
to really think much about being underground, or if you're, you know, a metro worker, and you are in tunnels under the city
才会真正想到在地下，或者如果你是一个地铁工人，你在城市地下的隧道里
where trains go
火车行驶的地方
But I'm just wondering if your experience with SubT has changed the way you think about in some ways, being in the world because your mind is so much underground.
但我只是想知道，你在SubT的经历是否在某些方面改变了你思考的方式，在这个世界上，因为你的思想在地下这么多。
Hey, yeah, well. I'll say everything takes a different lens when you put in the context of each of these tester programs and SubT is no different
嘿，是的，嗯。我想说的是，当你把这些测试者项目的背景放在一起时，一切都会有不同的镜头，SubT也不例外。
I think everything from when I am, you know, I don't know about if
我认为一切从我的时候，你知道，我不知道如果
you know, once upon a time, many ways, you know, taking a look every time I go.
你知道，很久以前，很多方式，你知道，每次我走的时候都会看一眼。
Or I go into a tunnel while I'm driving, or anything along those lines now, kind of inspires a little bit of SubT
或者我在开车的时候进入一个隧道，或者现在沿着这些路线的任何东西，有点激发了SubT的一点。
And I say, for anyone who watches movies quite a lot,
我说，对于任何一个经常看电影的人来说。
there are many occasions where there're folks in underground tunnels
有很多情况下，有的人在地下隧道里
or there're basements, there're empty malls in sublevels or whatever.
或有地下室，有空的商场在次层或其他地方。
so now that I watch those movies with the SubT challenge lens.
因此，现在我用SubT比赛镜头看这些电影时，我经常会大喊："我是谁？
I'm often shouting out oh that's a great idea for the SubT challenge,
我经常大喊，哦，这是一个关于SubT比赛的好主意。
but I maybe the other more technical, serious answer here is, I think, thinking about the underground has led me to understand that the challenges are quite severe --
但我也许在这里的另一个更技术性、更严肃的答案是，我认为，对地下的思考使我明白，挑战是相当严峻的 --
You don't have GPS, and often times something we lean on to get the job done for for a robot
你没有GPS，而很多时候，对于机器人来说，我们需要依靠它来完成工作。
Communication is horrible down there
下面的通信是很糟糕的
And so it makes us think a little bit differently about what it means to want to communicate what information do I want to share
所以这让我们对想要沟通的意义有了不同的思考，我想分享什么信息？
And this isn't just for robots, it turned out that this is applicable to human teams that go down there as well
这不仅仅是针对机器人的，事实证明，这也适用于人类团队在下面的工作。
so that given both a stronger, inspirational motivation to push the boundaries of those technologies,
因此，这给了我们一个更强大的、鼓舞人心的动力来推动这些技术的边界。
but it's also really driven the appreciation, not just by me but also of all the participants of the challenges that resided underground.
但它也真正推动了赞赏，不仅是我，还有所有参与者对地下的挑战的赞赏。
Well, thanks Tim, for sharing some of your personal notes from the underground and the challenges of working in Subterranean settings
好吧，感谢蒂姆，分享你在地下的一些个人笔记和在地下环境中工作的挑战。
And now let me pass the baton(指挥棒) back to Tabatha.
现在让我把接力棒传回给塔巴莎。
Thank you, Ivan.
谢谢你，伊万。
Tim, you talked about your experience, working with graduate students from the SubT challenge perspective
蒂姆，你谈到了你的经验，从SubT比赛的角度与研究生一起工作。
But you worked with students in an earlier challenge when you first came to DARPA for the swarm challeng, could you describe that program and what you learn from it?
但是，当你第一次来到DARPA进行蜂群挑战时，你在更早的挑战中与学生一起工作，你能描述一下那个项目以及你从那里学到了什么吗？
I know we talk about how I found my way to DARPA earlier, but in fact, I think it was
我知道我们谈到了我是如何在早期找到DARPA的，但事实上，我认为是
The swarm challenge concept that really seal the deal for bringing me to DARPA
蜂群挑战的概念，真正封住了我进入DARPA的路。
And this idea was building on the research I done previously of getting large teams of air vehicles
而这个想法是建立在我之前所做的关于让大型飞行器团队的研究之上的。
In this case, my prior research was on getting 50 fixed-wing aircraft, the fixed-wing airplane-like drones aloft(在空中) and doing interesting things in the sky
在这种情况下，我之前的研究是让50架固定翼飞机，即类似于固定翼飞机的无人机升空，在天空中做有趣的事情。
And we were able to leverage that body of work
我们能够利用这一工作成果
and the idea that came from it, and what we built out here at DARPA
和由此产生的想法，以及我们在DARPA这里建立的东西
upon my arrival was the service academies, swarm challenge that you referenced,
我们在DARPA建立了一个服务学院，就是你提到的蜂群挑战。
this was really fun because we wanted to capitalize on this momentum of technology development of getting large numbers of aircraft aloft
这真的很有趣，因为我们想利用这个技术发展的势头，让大量的飞机飞上天空
and also create an opportunity to help frame the next generation of military officer by working with the military services academies
并创造一个机会，通过与各军种学院的合作，帮助培养下一代的军官
Namely the naval academy, air force academy and the military academy at west point
即海军学院、空军学院和西点军校
and bring those cadets and midshipmen and work with them to understand what it means to work with these types of swarm technologies
并把这些学员和军校生带来，与他们一起工作，以了解与这些类型的蜂群技术合作意味着什么。
And the phrase we like to use was, how do you go from zero to swarm in 8 months
我们喜欢用的一句话是，你如何在8个月内从零到蜂群？
because that was the time, these cadets and midshipmen had in their capstone design projects in their senior year to complete this, this project
因为那是时间，这些学员和海军陆战队员在他们大四的毕业设计项目中要完成这个，这个项目
And so that was basically getting a fixed wing and quadrotor drones
所以这基本上是得到一个固定翼和四旋翼的无人机
I gave each team, and they get to pick their own lineup of 25 drones on the side
我给了每个团队，他们可以自己挑选25架无人机的阵容。
We set up bounty castles on the opposing sides of the field, and this is in lifelike experimentation, and so we have bounty castles and you'll score points by landing your drones in the opposing teams'
我们在场地的对立面设置了悬赏城堡，这是在进行栩栩如生的实验，所以我们有悬赏城堡，你的无人机降落在对方的悬赏城堡里就能得分。
bounty castle, but you want to defend your own home, bounty castle, of course, basically a simulated laser tag in the sky
赏金城堡，但你想保卫自己的家园，赏金城堡，当然，基本上是一个模拟的天空中的激光游戏。
And so it was this really great understanding how do you play strong offensive, how do you play strong defense
所以这是一个非常好的理解，你如何发挥强大的进攻，你如何发挥强大的防守
and have a gears turned for these cadets, who had never worked with the this type of technology before and partnering them with research engineers and lives and others to make this all happen
这些学员以前从未接触过这种类型的技术，他们与研究工程师、生命和其他人合作，使这一切成为现实。
It was incredibly rewarding to see cardets and midshipmen who never thought that they would be part of something that bold, that forward leaning in their time at the academies, I think,
我认为，看到那些从未想过自己会成为如此大胆的事情的一部分的学员和海军陆战队员，在他们在学院的时间里，这真是令人难以置信的收获。
and they walked away, recognizing that there does exists an organization within the DoD that is thinking so far in advance that they have the region to, 20, 21 year old to the start the process of tech revolution, right?
他们走了，认识到在国防部内确实存在着一个组织，他们提前考虑到了20、21岁开始技术革命进程的区域，对吗？
So I think that again, inspired me
所以我认为这再次启发了我
I think that that experience bolden and enforged(强化) my core team of challenge believers as a model for driving tech innovation,
我认为那段经历使我的核心团队的挑战者们更加大胆和坚定，成为推动科技创新的典范。
and that allowed us to go forward with kind of pitching the Subterranean challenge as the next bold step in driving autonomy and robotics technologies
这使我们能够继续推进 "地下挑战"，将其作为推动自主性和机器人技术的下一个大胆步骤。
And so let me just follow that with an institutional question,
因此，让我用一个机构问题来回答这个问题。
I mean, DARPA is a place where engineers like you
我的意思是，DARPA是一个地方，像你这样的工程师
Tim can develop a technology vision
蒂姆可以开发一个技术愿景
And as I see in the opening of this podcast -- redefine what is possible
正如我在这个播客的开头所看到的--重新定义什么是可能的
But what is it about DARPA institutionally, do you think, that creates these opportunities?
但是，你认为DARPA在体制上有什么特点，创造了这些机会？
I definitely believe DARPA has a secret sauce that it has continued to, been able to generate those ideas, but also create and execute and realize those ideas
我绝对相信DARPA有一个秘密的酱汁，它一直能够产生这些想法，也能够创造、执行和实现这些想法。
I think, on the one hand, certainly from the technical technology office, from which I hear,
我认为，一方面，当然是来自于技术技术办公室，从那里我听到。
we really love seeing technologies demonstrated so systems being brought together and realized in some sort of field test demonstration, and I think that's one end.
我们真的很喜欢看到技术展示，所以系统被汇集在一起，并在某种现场测试演示中实现，我想这是一个方面。
on the other hand
另一方面
We're interested in creating whole new, foundation whole new
我们对创造全新的、基础全新的
areas of research that hadn't really been thought about.
我们对创造全新的研究领域感兴趣，这些领域还没有真正被考虑过。
And I think that being able of expand that spectrum and do it in the context of, you know, one hundred or so of programming and across 300 programs is a pretty phenomenal(不寻常)
我认为，能够扩大这一范围，并在你知道的情况下，在100多个项目和300多个项目中做到这一点，是一个相当惊人的（不寻常）。
I'd say, one another way that I describe DARPA, this was, uh, one of my colleagues had previously described research this way
我想说的是，我描述DARPA的另一种方式，这是，呃，我的一个同事以前曾这样描述研究
Is there're a lot of folks out there that might say some research is impossible
有很多人可能会说有些研究是不可能的
or some vision is impossible
或一些设想是不可能的
And my colleague at the time said, actually no, it's not impossible
而我的同事当时说，其实不，这不是不可能的。
It's rather, it's unpossible
相反，它是不可能的。
It's just that it hasn't been done yet
只是它还没有被完成而已
It is not that it can't been done yet
并不是说它还不能做
and I like to embrace that philosophy and everything that I try to touch in the sense, just because I hadn't been done before
我喜欢接受这种哲学，以及我试图接触的所有东西的意义，只是因为我以前没有做过
is not proof that it can't be done.
并不证明它不能被做。
In fact, its challenge, say, that maybe I am the one who can do it,
事实上，它的挑战，说，也许我是一个可以做的人。
and DARPA really gives us both the tools and inspiration,
而DARPA确实给了我们工具和灵感。
and the kind of community, as to say, that both the support, but also my, you know, program manager colleagues, when I see all the amazing things they are making possible
和那种社区，可以说，无论是支持，但也是我的，你知道，项目经理的同事，当我看到所有惊人的事情，他们是可能的
it makes me think that the things might have been considered impossible, or simply just opportunities.
这让我想到，这些事情可能被认为是不可能的，或者仅仅是机会。
We're getting towards the end here, but I want to get into a couple of questions that are more about technology in general
我们在这里已经接近尾声，但我想进入几个更多关于一般技术的问题
First, I want to ask you about the kinds of technology is developing
首先，我想问你关于技术的种类正在发展。
We're talking now here, about humans and machines working together
我们现在在这里谈论的是人类和机器一起工作。
DARPA has a long long history going back even to 1960s, thinking about that particular kind of powerful dynamic.
DARPA有很长的历史，甚至可以追溯到1960年代，思考这种特殊的强大动力。
So I'm just wondering what excites you most about these technologies?
所以我只是想知道这些技术中最让你兴奋的是什么？
As you said it is the intersection of the human, machines synbiosis(协同生物) that is in a lot of DARPA's genetic code already
正如你所说的，人类和机器的协同生物（synbiosis）的交叉点已经在DARPA的许多遗传密码中。
So I am leveraging understanding on their shoulders for sure
所以我肯定是站在他们的肩膀上利用理解。
I think the thing that perhaps excites me a lot about these technologies
我认为这些技术最让我兴奋的地方是
is the idea that we'll have to look at our robotic teams in [fuck] different ways
是我们将不得不以不同的方式来看待我们的机器人团队。
What I mean by that is a lot of maybe a research has been done on what it means to
我的意思是说，很多研究也许已经完成了对单一机器人的工作意味着什么？
work with a single robot, or maybe a few robots, but we're narrowly pushing what it means to work with multiple, many robots
我的意思是，很多研究也许是针对与单个机器人，或者几个机器人一起工作所做的，但我们正在狭隘地推动与多个、许多机器人一起工作的含义
And I think this is a really rich area of new research to be had in the sense that the way I would interact with my small team of researchers, or at a startup company,
我认为这是一个非常丰富的新研究领域，在这个意义上，我与我的小型研究团队，或在创业公司的互动方式。
or something like that is very different men, how I would want to interact a larger company or a larger project team, and that goes analogously(类似的) with team of robots
或类似的东西是非常不同的，我想与一个更大的公司或更大的项目团队进行互动，这与机器人团队的情况类似（类似的）。
And so I think how we work with mixed, but physically mixed in terms of your air and ground, but uh mixed as in the functions that these robots will play in a composition of a team
因此，我认为我们如何与混合的工作，但在你的空气和地面方面的物理混合，但呃混合作为这些机器人将发挥的功能，在一个团队的组成
I think the type of [...] is really gonna open up not only new capabilities, but also plane proceeds for new foundation of research to be done as well
我认为这种类型的[......]真的会开辟新的能力，也会为新的研究基础提供平面收益。
So that's gonna be one of the, interestingly, behind, if I can say that, both of these problems, is understanding what it means to work when you have high complexity in a robot team itself,
因此，有趣的是，如果我可以这么说的话，这两个问题的背后，是理解当你在机器人团队中拥有高复杂性时，工作意味着什么。
and that warrants high complexity, warrants new math, new communication networks, new compute methodologies, new sensing approaches or new algorithms
而这需要高复杂度，需要新的数学，新的通信网络，新的计算方法，新的传感方法或新的算法
And I think both of these programs have started to, bear some of the fruit out and lay some of the foundations
我认为这两个项目已经开始结出一些果实，并奠定了一些基础。
So that's been really, really exciting.
所以这真的是非常，非常令人兴奋。
And that's a lot of foundation to lay down
这是一个需要打下的很多基础
We all know how much it takes for people to work well together
我们都知道，人们要想很好地合作，需要付出多大的努力
So I'm not surprised to hear about the enormity(棘手) and complexity of the task to realize the mission in which humans and machines work together almost as if they were one hybrid organism, very cool stuff.
因此，我听到关于实现任务的艰巨性（棘手）和复杂性并不感到惊讶，在这个任务中，人类和机器一起工作，几乎就像他们是一个混合生物体，非常酷的东西。
It is, and I think it's important to know how that work is continuing
确实如此，我认为了解这项工作的进展情况很重要。
I've been reference
我一直在参考
at the beginning of the episode, but there is no doubt Covid19 will be an historic marker for all of our lives.
在这一集的开头，但毫无疑问，Covid19将是我们所有生活中的一个历史标志。
It would be interesting to know, Tim, how it is affected your work, and perhaps the near term goals in deliverables for some of these programs you're working on.
有意思的是，蒂姆，它是如何影响你的工作的，也许你正在进行的这些项目的近期目标是什么？
Yeah, no doubt Covid19 has had its impact, one of the things about DARPA is that it's all about being able to be nimble(灵活) and adaptive,
是的，毫无疑问，Covid19有它的影响，DARPA的一个特点是，它是所有关于能够灵活（灵活）和适应的。
and so I think, even in the context of OFFSET and SubT challenge, the impact really is felt in the context of, as I mentioned earlier, is about trying to get robots in the real world
所以我认为，即使在OFFSET和SubT比赛的背景下，也能真正感受到其影响，正如我之前提到的，是关于试图让机器人在现实世界中使用的。
And when it's difficult to go to the real world to get those lessons learned and put a robot in those context, which, which Covid19 is really limited our ability to do that, it definitely does impact the type of progres and lessons learned we can achieve
当我们很难去现实世界获得这些经验教训，并将机器人置于这些环境中时，Covid19确实限制了我们这样做的能力，这肯定会影响我们能够实现的进展和经验教训的类型。
But in that same vein, both of these problems have a theme of leveraging the virtual environment to, kind of, balance in couple and accelerate the lessons that we learn in the real world
但同样地，这两个问题都有一个主题，即利用虚拟环境来平衡和加速我们在现实世界中所学到的经验。
And so, in OFFSET we have two virtual environments that allow us to explore, test, simulate swarm tactics and execution
因此，在OFFSET中，我们有两个虚拟环境，允许我们探索、测试、模拟蜂群战术和执行。
And we do that with realistic environment. In test site we will have a 3D model of a test site, and we'll replicate what it is that we're testing in a synthetic environment
我们在真实的环境中做到这一点。在测试场地，我们将有一个测试场地的三维模型，我们将复制我们在合成环境中测试的内容。
And the OFFSET program was structured from getgo whether there're robot, whether they're simulated real, don't know that they're plugged in to the simulated world.
而OFFSET项目从一开始就结构化，无论是否有机器人，无论他们是否是模拟的真实，都不知道他们被插入到模拟的世界中。
So we really leaned to that aspect, the OFFSET programs so that we can still continue to discover new ideas and strengthen the insights that we hope or translate to
因此，我们真的倾向于这方面，OFFSET计划，以便我们仍然可以继续发现新的想法，加强我们希望或转化为的见解。
the fourth dominic field test of OFFSET program for the SubT challenge again, that virtual environment plays a huge role for SubT and since that we have the virtual competition alongside the system's competition
第四次多米尼克实地测试OFFSET项目的SubT比赛，虚拟环境对SubT起到了巨大的作用，因此我们在系统的竞争中也有虚拟竞争。
So whereas(然而) we might be physically putting robots in underground environments, for the system's competition
因此，虽然我们可能会把机器人放在地下环境中，但对于系统的比赛来说
we've created that SubT simulator that allows for teams to not only practice and test, but also compete in virtual environment
我们已经创建了SubT模拟器，允许团队不仅练习和测试，而且在虚拟环境中竞争
And so that virtual environment has given us another opportunity,
所以这个虚拟环境给了我们另一个机会。
and in some ways of relief alf for teams, who are constrained and being able to go to the site, to go on the test, I can still do some of that development in the simulated contexts to go
在某种程度上缓解了团队的压力，他们受到限制，无法去现场，无法进行测试，我仍然可以在模拟的环境中进行一些开发，去
and and you know keeping the ball rolling forward, 'cause OFFSET and SubT both about keeping up the momentum of a research, just like the rest of DARPA. I'd one of the other
和你知道保持球滚动前进，因为OFFSET和SubT都是关于保持研究的势头，就像DARPA的其他部分。其他影响之一
impacts, of course, is that community I described earlier about getting people together and facilitating the exchange of information or bouncing ideas or seeing what works
当然，另一个影响是我之前描述的社区，即让人们聚集在一起，促进信息交流或碰撞想法，或看到什么是有效的
imitating it in my own research, or whatever I mean,
在我自己的研究中模仿它，或任何我的意思。
each of these teams benefits from the interaction in very different, but also in profound ways fastering the sense of community, through online community forum, or being able to open up a collaborative web space for teams to share their software
这些团队中的每一个人都从互动中受益，但也有很深的意义 通过在线社区论坛，或者能够为团队分享他们的软件开辟一个合作的网络空间，加快社区的感觉
deliverables are ways that were trying to live in this normal.
这些都是我们试图在这种正常情况下生活的方式。
Tim, thank you for your time, for your insights into your work with DARPA.
蒂姆，感谢你的时间，感谢你对你在DARPA工作的见解。
It's been a pleasure
这是我的荣幸。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢你。
I will encourage everyone to spend some time exploring the SubT challenge, play list on DARPA's youtube channel, to get an idea of how teams are tackling the underground
我鼓励大家花一些时间探索SubT比赛，DARPA的youtube频道上的播放列表，以了解团队如何解决地下问题。
You can see a couple of recent OFFSET field experiments on the youtube channel as well
你也可以在youtube频道上看到最近的几个OFFSET现场实验。
And Ivan, it's been great joing you as the co-hosts
伊万，很高兴与你一起担任共同主持人。
I look forward to seeing you back in the studio.
我期待着在演播室看到你回来。
Yes, and it was my pleasure too to share
是的，我也很高兴能与你分享
this is a tag team podcast with you Tabatha, and also just to learn so much about what you're doing
这也是我的荣幸，能和你塔巴塔一起做播客，也能了解到很多你所做的事情。
Tim, It's been really, really fascinating
蒂姆，这真的非常，非常吸引人。
And thanks listeners for sharing this time with us, I hope you join us again for the next Voices from DARPA.
感谢听众与我们分享这段时光，我希望你能再次加入我们的下一期DARPA之声。
For more information about Dr. Timothy Chung, his programs and the other breakthrough technology DARPA is working on, visit DARPA.mil
欲了解更多关于Timothy Chung博士、他的项目以及DARPA正在研究的其他突破性技术的信息，请访问DARPA.mil。